Kay Rubio

Software Engineer

ksweeneyrubio@gmail.com

802-318-6288 GitHub Melrose, MA <u>LinkedIn</u>

Education

BS in Computer Science

Framingham State University: 2019 - 2022 GPA: 3.95/4.00 | Outstanding Computer Science Senior Award

MA in Psychology*

Clark University: 2014 - 2016

(no letter grades) | Research assistantship

MS in Counseling*

UMASS Boston: 2012 - 2014

GPA: 4.00/4.00 | Research assistantship

BA in Social Studies

Ithaca College: 2006 - 2009

GPA: 3.74/4.00 | President's Scholarship

*Transferrable skills:

Data analysis, statistical programming, psycholinguistics, teamwork, public speaking, written communication

Skills

Front end: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript/ES6,

TypeScript, React, Redux

Data science: Python, Java, R, SQL, SAS,

scikit-learn

Environments/Tools: git, Jira, JupyterLab,

RStudio

Summary

Excited for opportunities to grow in machine learning and voice data analysis. Nearly 3 years of experience in front-end web development with exploratory projects in machine learning. 5+ years of experience in statistics and data analysis.

Work Experience

Software Engineer II

Jan 2022 - Present | Curriculum Associates, LLC

- Code React components and automated tests for interactive education applications
- Ensure web technologies are accessible to users who are blind, deaf, or have other disabilities
- Code programs that use natural language processing and machine learning to analyze text

Senior Research Data Manager

Oct 2018 - Dec 2021 | Carelon Research (formerly HealthCore)

- Built the largest research database in the US and Canada on children hospitalized with COVID-19
- Coded programs in SAS/SQL to identify complex data issues and increase data cleaning efficiency
- Led meetings to present progress with scientists, statisticians, and other stakeholders

Clinical Research Coordinator II

May 2016 - Oct 2018 | Massachusetts General Hospital

 Coordinated research on aphasia and other language disorders, built databases and organized data collection

Example Machine Learning Projects

<u>Topic Modeling</u> (2024): Used natural language processing and unsupervised machine learning algorithms to identify underlying themes in 20,000 Dear Abby questions from 1985-2017.

<u>Regression Project</u> (2024): Trained models to predict danceability scores from the temporal features of 13,000 songs. Compared results of Gradient Boosting, Random Forest, Multivariate Linear Regression, and Multilayer Perceptron.

<u>Classifier Project</u> (2024): Trained models to predict hospital readmission in patients with diabetes. Compared results of Random Forest, Gradient Boosting, Logistic Regression, Multilayer Perceptron, and K-Neighbors.